Good to see every every everybody. Um
brain's a little fried right now. Um
First off, just kind of want to thank
the staff, uh the scouting staff, the
coaches, football operations, everybody
involved for what we feel is a
successful draft. Uh we felt like we
definitely got better. We challenged the
roster in a lot of spots. Um gained
gained a lot of depth in a lot in a lot
of areas.
Um so yeah, we feel
feel good about what we accomplished
during the draft and excited about
things moving forward and we're
obviously headed in the right direction,
so um with that, I'll open it up to any
questions.
We'll kick things off with Joe Person.
Hey Dan. Uh um What's up, Joe? Good good
to see you, man. You too. Get getting a
little dark over here. All right, you're
good. Um once you traded back to 227,
um
what about the the I heard you talk
about um challenging the roster and
building depth. Did did you draft anyone
this weekend you think will start from
day one?
Um you know, I think everybody that we
drafted, you know, I think they'll all
have the opportunity to compete um and
that's what we're all about here, myself
and coach and the rest of the staff. We
want to bring guys in to challenge the
roster and have them compete and you
know, we brought we brought in a bunch
of competitors during this draft and
they're going to have a chance to
compete and show us what they can do and
uh it'll be fun to watch.
Which of these guys do you think has the
best chance to make the biggest,
earliest impact? Uh I think it's up to
them. You know, I think I'm uh
excited about all the guys that we
drafted, otherwise, you know, we
wouldn't have drafted them, so they're
all going to have the opportunity to
come in and compete and we're excited to
see what they can do.
Are you considering bringing in another
uh
undrafted quarterback? Uh potentially.
Potentially, we'll we'll do that and
have four quarterbacks, which we really
haven't had since I don't think we've
been here, but yeah, there's definitely
the potential for for that. You think
it's likely?
Yeah, I do. Okay. Yeah.
Alex Zietlow.
Hey Dan, congrats on um getting through
another NFL draft. Thanks. What's up,
Alex? What's up, man? Um
uh particularly on day three, there
seemed to be a couple guys who um
uh who fell to you guys.
Um particularly uh Zaquandre Whiteley
and um
and Sam Hecht. Are those two guys, when
you had the opportunity to draft them,
were were you surprised that they were
still available at um when you got the
chance to take them? Uh yeah, a little
bit. You know, I think uh I think you
saw us kind of maneuver around the board
a little bit. Uh just looking at our
board, you know, we had a handful
players that we had up there, so we're
like, "Hey,
we like these guys." Like they're all
guys that we feel like can help us, so
we're like, "Let's trade back. Let's
gain more picks, gain more value."
And you know, we did that and then and
it worked out in our favor at the end.
Specifically about Zaquandre, how do you
see him fitting into the this defense?
Yeah, you know, just a big, long,
physical guy. Um he fits the DNA that we
want, the type of competitor that we
want. Um he can play the post, he can
play up in the box, he can do a lot of
things for our defense that we're
excited about.
Any more questions?
Cassie.
Hey Dan, how's it going? What's up,
Cassie?
Um you had a couple of guys today that
made it through college or at least the
last couple of years without a single
penalty. Is that just kind of a
coincidence or is that something that
y'all value and look at? I mean,
obviously, we don't want penalties. Um I
think it's more a coincidence than than
anything. Um
but honestly, I didn't even really know
that. That's kind of cool, though.
Yeah, I think it was uh
Whiteley and Hecht made it through
without a penalty in college or at least
last couple of years.
And then on Will Lee specifically, he he
comes off the tape like really just kind
of tenacious. How important is that in a
safety back there?
Yeah, you know, corner, safety, um
that's what we want, you know, that's
our identity. You know, we want to be
physical, we want to be tough, we want
to be competitive and you know, we we're
drafting those type of guys in our
culture and um you know, I think every
one of those guys that we drafted, you
know, from the first round all the way
down to the seventh, they they embody
that.
Daron Gantt followed by Mike Kaye.
Dan, specifically to Hecht at center,
what did you guys see in him that you
like and and how do you see him
competing right out of the gate? Yeah,
he's going to have a chance to compete.
Um I think first and foremost, you see
his initial quickness. Uh he's really
good with angles. You know, he can reach
guys. He's good with his hands, getting
his hands inside, controlling blockers
and staying staying sticky on blocks. Um
I would say is the biggest thing with
him, staying on his feet, keeping his
balance. Um he's another guy that can
work to the second level. He can get out
in space as a puller. Um so there's a
lot of things that we like about him.
Was it a priority for you this weekend
to to make that room not only deeper,
but younger as you look at the makeup of
the offensive line as a whole? Yeah, you
know, I I definitely think we need to
add some youth in there, you know, on
the interior and outside at tackle and
feel like we accomplished that and you
know, we'll do some things in undrafted
free agency as well that'll again add to
the competition and the and the depth
out there.
Hey Dan, thanks for doing this. Yeah.
I'm setting myself up to be made fun of
because of how I pronounce the kids'
name uh by Joe.
Uh Jackson, the guy you just added from
Miami of Ohio. Um
do you see him as kind of a special
teams cog or what what's your outlook on
him? He doesn't have a lot of playing
time prior to last year. Yeah, good
player, uh really good instincts. He can
run, he plays fast. Uh he sees it really
well.
Uh a guy that we're obviously excited
about. You know, I think he's definitely
going to be able to contribute on
special teams and again, like like every
area, like he's going to have a chance
to compete and show us what he can do.
And then
with Will Lee, um do you see him
primarily working outside boundary wise?
I know he brought up how much he likes
doing press man, but obviously that's
not something you guys do a ton. Um do
you guys see him as like a long-term
outside cornerback? Yeah, um you know, I
think obviously, I'll leave that up to
the coaches for what they want to do
with him. Um at Texas A&M, he played on
the outside and he's really good at
press and and I think he's a guy that as
he continues to grow and mature in the
game, he'll be able to, you know, figure
out off coverage and some of the things
that we do schematically. I think he's
just a really good fit for us by the way
he plays, the temperament he plays with,
the swag he plays with out there. Uh
just a guy that we really loved.
Joe Person followed by Sheena Quick.
Um
Dan is Dan or Dave can address this or
both of you. Kind of following up on
Daron's question.
Were was this a draft where
you you guys wanted to, you know, kind
of look long-term more so maybe than
than short-term?
Uh I'll answer that. I mean, I won't For
for me, it's always about right now. Uh
this season and what we're doing and um
trying to make sure that we can get the
most out of our guys that we currently
have. We always start with our roster,
but then, you know, trying to find guys
that fit the traits and characteristics,
personality of who the Panthers are.
Um and that's what we were looking for
is just get more of that and uh it's
going to be the same thing every year.
You know, can we how can we make the
2026 Panthers the best possible unit
that we can make it and um if we have
guys that, you know, bring a certain
skill set at any position uh to give
them a chance to compete and be out
there, you know, we just felt feel like
it elevates the whole group.
And then back to Dan. Um is
there's a lot all every year, I really
since you took over, people uh and you
have drafted tight ends, but I there's
this feeling I think that you guys need
to go get a tight end a
number one tight end. Is that shared in
in the building or
I don't know. You you addressed it a
little bit last week.
>> Yeah, we have a we have a lot of
confidence in the guys that are on our
roster and I said that before, you know,
with Tommy and with Mitch and with
Jatavion and James Mitchell and you
know, we we have some guys that we're
excited about and you know,
again, we'll always look for, you know,
avenues to make the roster better. If we
feel like we need to, you know, figure
figure out tight end and bring a
different skill set in, then we'll do
that, but right now, we feel good about
it. And then Dan, any positions where
you feel like you're still maybe a
little light, whether it's inside
linebacker, even corner?
Uh you know, I think again, we're we're
always going to find ways. We're never
going to be content. We're never we're
never just going to sit there. We're
just going to try to add as much depth
and competition to the roster as
possible and
you know, we'll we'll keep doing that
moving forward.
Good afternoon, guys. How are you? Good.
How you doing?
Um just a question about uh Lee and
Whiteley. What specifically did you guys
see in those two players that made them
a fit for the corner and safety rooms
that you guys have right now?
Lee Lee and Wheatley?
Yeah, Will Lee. Oh, yeah.
Um, you want to go?
>> Yeah, I'll take it. Yeah. Um, you know,
we look for play style first and
foremost. Um,
trying to project, you know, the the
athletic ability
to contribute is obviously a big part of
it. But then, once we kind of know and
identify guys that we feel like can can
impact us and can play in the NFL from
an athletic standpoint, then we go to
play style. And you know, Will Lee, Dan
kind of talked about it a little bit,
the length, the aggressiveness, his
ability to play physical
at the at the attack point, whether it's
on bubble screens or getting involved in
the run game. We ask our corners to
tackle, you know, and and be a part of
the fits
in our system with our cracker place
rules and different things like that.
So, we felt like he really fit that
mold. And then, for Z Wheatley, he's
just a really instinctive player,
physical player, shows up downhill,
takes really good angles, runs downhill.
He's all over the field and
you know, just that kind of activity on
the back half is it's really crucial for
how we play football and and guys being
able to see the formation, anticipate
concepts, and then show up physically
and play with that type of attitude that
we're looking for. We had a great time
you know, meeting with Zakhia at the
combine and just kind of picking his
brain about what he knew, what he was
looking for and
where he came from and how he's become
the player that he's come. And we just
loved all the background and everything
and it really shows on on film and
he was one of my favorite guys just
through the process to see him in the
play style that he brought.
Thanks, guys.
We have time for just a few more. We'll
go back to Mike Kaye.
Hey Dave,
this running back class is not
particularly deep at least from the
outside looking in and in the selections
that were made. You've had Jonathan in
the program for about a week. Obviously,
you're not doing any contacts. You
drafted Etienne last year.
I know we're talking about the moves you
did make, but the fact that you guys
didn't push for a running back with how
much you publicly talk about wanting to
run the ball. What does that say about
those two guys and your guys' outlook on
them?
Well, it goes beyond that, too. You
know, AJ Dillon's here. You know, Trey
Tyson's guy we're really excited about
getting to see
coming up here when we get into camp in
the preseason games. And and and
Montrell's another guy who, you know,
played at a really high level in college
and and is is finding his way in the
pros. But we were able to bring those
guys in. We're excited to see what they
can do. And when we start with this
process, we always, you know, as we're
looking at players in the draft, we kind
of look at them compared to our roster,
compared to the guys we have.
Who is this guy competing with in this
room? Like where do we see them being
able to try to affect it? And we got a
bunch of guys that we're really excited
about. And you know, of course you
talked about
Jonathan and and Trevor, you know, um,
in in that conversation as well. And and
we have high hopes for Jonathan, you
know, and and he looks great right now.
Can't wait to, you know, in the smartest
way possible get him out there and
expose him at the right time and
and get him accustomed to the things
that we're doing. But um,
yeah, love that group. I love what
Bernie Parmalee's doing with them and
and how they attack it. And you know, we
kind of tell them you set the tone for
the offense. And so, we love the way
those guys are built.
And we haven't been able to talk to you
about it yet, but Trevon and JT do you
think both participating in the program
as well?
Yeah. Um, the Trevon came back he's he's
doing really great in terms of getting
back out there. JT's been cleared. He's
doing more and more. So, but right now
as we know, you know, they're it's
weight room and and meetings right now.
So, until we get onto the field and kind
of move them around, we still got to be
smart about all that stuff.
Yeah. Thank you.
All right, guys. That's all the
questions we have for you today. Thank
you so much for taking the time. Thanks,
guys. All right, thank you.
>> [music]
[music]